MIESC - Multi-layer Intelligent Evaluation for Smart Contracts
A Defense-in-Depth Security Framework
MIESC combines 25+ security analysis tools
across 9 specialized layers
Designed for developers, security researchers,
and audit firms
Let's explore the 9-layer architecture
Each layer provides a different security perspective
Layer 1: Static Analysis with Slither, Aderyn, Solhint
Layer 2: Pattern Detection with SmartBugsDetector
Layer 3: Symbolic Execution with Mythril, Manticore
Layer 4: Fuzzing with Echidna, Medusa, DogeFuzz
Layer 5: Formal Verification with Certora, Halmos
Layer 6: ML Detection with DA-GNN, SmartGuard
Layer 7: AI Analysis with SmartLLM, PropertyGPT
Layer 8: DeFi Security with MEV and oracle analyzers
Layer 9: Dependency Scanning for CVE detection
Now let's analyze a vulnerable smart contract
This contract has multiple vulnerabilities:
Reentrancy, missing access control, timestamp dependence
Running the 9-layer Defense-in-Depth scan
Each layer analyzes the contract from a different angle
Static analysis detects code patterns
Symbolic execution explores all execution paths
Analysis complete! 5 vulnerabilities detected
2 Critical, 1 High, 1 Medium, 1 Low
Critical: Reentrancy vulnerability in withdraw()
External call before state update allows attacks
Critical: Unrestricted setBalance() function
Anyone can modify user balances
Each finding includes detailed remediation guidance
With code examples for the fix
MIESC generates professional audit reports
In HTML, PDF, and JSON formats
Reports include executive summary, risk score,
detailed findings, and tool evidence
Scientific validation on SmartBugs benchmark:
84.3% recall, 80% F1-score
Easy CLI integration for developers
miesc analyze MyContract.sol --deep
GitHub Actions integration for CI/CD
Automatic security scanning on every PR
Python API for security researchers
Integrate MIESC into your audit workflow
Opening the generated HTML audit report
Professional format ready for clients
Risk score visualization and severity breakdown
All findings with SWC and CWE references
Tool evidence preserved for audit trail
Slither, Mythril, and other tool outputs included
MIESC - Making smart contract security accessible
Open source under AGPL-3.0 license
Get started: pip install miesc
GitHub: github.com/fboiero/MIESC
Developed by Fernando Boiero at UNDEF - IUA Córdoba
Star us on GitHub!